Guide to the Louise Crane and Victoria Kent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Louise Crane and Victoria Kent papers
1809-1998
YCAL MSS 473
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
31.17
(39 boxes) + 1 roll
The Louise Crane and Victoria Kent Papers document the personal and professional lives of Louise Crane, Victoria Kent, and Josephine Boardman Crane, and consist of correspondence, subject files, personal papers, financial documents, clippings, photographs, and slides. The papers provide evidence of the Crane family's philanthropic work and involvement in a number of cultural associations, including the China Institute in America, Harpsichord Music Society, Metropolitan Museum of Art, and Museum of Modern Art. Correspondents include Elizabeth Bishop and Loren MacIver. The Papers provide insight into a prominent philanthropic family as well as cultural activities in New York City during the mid- to late twentieth century. Victoria Kent's involvement in politics and cultural affairs is also represented in the Papers. Victoria Kent's correspondence and subject files are a window into the activities of the expatriate Spanish community in the United States following the Spanish Civil War. The papers also relate to Crane and Kent's work to publish the Spanish-language magazine Ibérica as well as their personal relationship.
Crane, Louise
Crane, Josephine Boardman, 1873-1972
Kent, Victoria, 1892-1987
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Louise Crane, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 39: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Josephine Boardman Crane Papers (YCAL MSS 292). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Louise Crane (1913-1997)
Louise Crane, born on November 11, 1913, was the daughter of Josephine Boardman Crane (1873-1972) and W. Murray Crane (1853-1920). She attended Vassar where she became friends with Elizabeth Bishop and Margaret Miller among others. Crane and Bishop befriended Marianne Moore, who became a mentor and lifelong friend (Crane had power of attorney for Moore at the end of her life). Following her graduation from Vassar, Louise Crane was involved in a number of cultural institutions and programs, including the Harpsichord Music Society and the Museum of Modern Art. Josephine Boardman Crane, with help from Louise, hosted a number of literary salons at their home at 820 Fifth Avenue, New York. The Cranes' apartment was filled with decorative arts and artwork and the Cranes lent and donated a number of pieces to museums. In addition to their home in Manhattan, the Crane family owned homes in Woods Hole, Ma. ("Driftwood"), Dalton, Ma., Redding, Ct., and Fort Myers Beach, Florida. In later years Louise Crane lived with and assisted her aging mother.
Among the circle of writers whom the Cranes befriended were Djuna Barnes, Elizabeth Bishop, Bryher, Loren MacIver, Somerset Maugham, Marianne Moore, Edith and Osbert Sitwell, Virgil Thomson, Glenway Wescott, and Tennessee Williams.
Bishop and Crane traveled extensively together, including trips to Europe, Morocco, and the Atlas Mountains (1935-1936), Florida (1936-1937), and Ireland, France, and Italy (1937). In 1938 they bought a home in Key West, Florida. Crane commuted between New York, where she took care of her mother, and Key West. Crane and Bishop stopped traveling together after 1940.
Crane died in 1997 after suffering from Alzheimer's for a number of years.
Crane's mother, Josephine Boardman Crane, was a prominent philanthropist; she developed the "Dalton Plan," a progressive method of education, which led to the founding of the Dalton School, and was one of the founders of the Museum of Modern Art. A member of the family who owned the Crane Paper Company, in Dalton, Massachusetts, W. Murray Crane entered politics and served as governor of Massachusetts (1900-1902) and as state senator for Massachusetts (1904-1914). Louise Crane was one of the couple's three children; her two brothers were Bruce Crane (who became President of the Crane Paper Company) and Stephen Crane.
Victoria Kent (1892-1987)
Victoria Kent was Louise Crane's companion in later years. Kent was a prominent lawyer and politician from Spain. She was born on March 6, 1892 in Málaga. (During her lifetime Kent maintained she was born in 1897, however, organizers of an homage to Kent in Málaga discovered in 1997 that her birth date is in fact 1892.) As a young woman Kent studied law at the University of Madrid and after graduation she became the first female lawyer in Spain. She gained notoriety as a lawyer in 1931 when she was one of the defense lawyers for politicians Fernando de los Rios, Niceto Alcalá-Zamora, Francisco Largo Cabellero, and Álvaro de Albornoz. She served as a congresswoman in the Parliament of the Second Spanish Republic (1931) and as Director General of Prisons (1931-1934) but was forced to flee Spain during the Spanish civil war. Kent lived in exile in France (recounted in her book Cuatro Años en París ) and served as the Secretary of the Spanish Embassy (1937-1939). Kent lived for a period in Mexico -- where she taught penal law at the University of Mexico -- and then moved to the United States where she worked as a member of the Secretariat for the United Nations (1950-1952). Crane and Kent published Ibérica, a Spanish language anti-Franco magazine from 1954 to 1974. Following Josephine Boardman Crane's death, Kent and Crane lived together in Woods Hole, Massachusetts, and Redding, Connecticut.
Kent died of a heart attack in September 1987.
Scope and Contents
The Louise Crane and Victoria Kent Papers document the personal and professional lives of Louise Crane, Victoria Kent, and Josephine Boardman Crane, and consist of correspondence, subject files, personal papers, financial documents, clippings, photographs, and slides. The papers provide evidence of the Crane family's philanthropic work and involvement in a number of cultural associations, including the China Institute, Harpsichord Music Society, Metropolitan Museum of Art, and Museum of Modern Art. The Papers provide insight into a prominent philanthropic family as well as cultural activities in New York City during the mid- to late twentieth century. Victoria Kent's involvement in politics and cultural affairs is also represented in the Papers. Victoria Kent's correspondence and subject files are a window into the activities of the expatriate Spanish community in the United States following the Spanish Civil War.
Louise Crane lived with and cared for her aging mother -- not only providing company but also serving as a secretary -- and for this reason the papers of Louise and Josephine Boardman Crane are intermingled. The Cranes hosted literary and musical events at their home on Fifth Avenue; these events are captured in their correspondence and subject files (such as "Monday afternoon literary class") that trace guests and topics of conversation. Their home was full of decorative arts and artwork; its decor is recorded in subject files and photographs. The Cranes' friends included a number of authors and artists. Correspondents include: Elizabeth Bishop, Loren MacIver, and Virgil Thomson. The Cranes' financial support for a number of artists and cultural institutions is represented in their financial documents. The papers also include documents pertaining to Cranes family members, such as correspondence and photographs of Josephine Boardman Crane's sister, Mabel Thorp Boardman (1860-1946), who was Secretary of the American National Red Cross.
Victoria Kent's involvement in politics and her work with Louise Crane to publish Ibérica are documented in her correspondence and subject files (which include several copies of the publication). Kent's legal work and interest in prison reform are also represented in various documents. A native of Spain, Kent worked tirelessly on projects relating to her mother country as well as the wellfare of Spaniards displaced by the civil war and World War II, as her files on Comité Popular de Ayuda los Refugiados Españoles and Spanish Refugee Aid demonstrate.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Louise Crane Papers, 1809-1998. II. Harpsichord Music Society, 1957-1992. III. Victoria Kent Papers, 1936-1988.
Ibérica (New York, N.Y.: 1953); Art patrons -- United States; Music patrons -- United States; Philanthropists -- United States; Women lawyers -- Spain; Women philanthropists -- United States; Women politicians -- Spain; Spain -- History -- 1939-1975; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939; Spain -- History Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives, Spanish; Spain -- History Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Women; Photographs; Slides; LGBTQ resource; Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979; Crane, Josephine Boardman, 1873-1972; Crane, Louise; Kent, Victoria, 1892-1987; MacIver, Loren, 1909-1998; China Institute in America; Harpsichord Music Society; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)
- Louise Crane Papers, 1809-1998; Series I; 12.42; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into four broad subseries: Correspondence and Subject Files; Personal Papers; Photographic Materials; and Financial Papers.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, writings, notes, financial papers, printed material, photographs, slides, and personal papers relating to Louise Crane, Josephine Boardman Crane, Victoria Kent, and other family members and friends.
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - American Red Cross, 1947-1997; 2 (Box 1)
    - Art correspondence, 1950-95 (Box 1)
    - Art objects loaned for exhibition, 1945-67 (Box 1)
    - Art-Grigoriev Portrait of Catherine Breshkovskaia, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Art-Carolyn Hortin & Associates (repairs), 1972 (Box 1)
    - Art-Melnitzky (Restorer), 1966-68 (Box 1)
    - Bean, Betty, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Benedictines. Abbey of St. Benoit du Lac (Box 1)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1960-85; 2 (Box 1)
      Includes photographs
    - Boardman, Mabel J., letters from:, 1809-1920
      - A (Box 1)
      - B (Box 1)
      - Boardman to Boardman, 4 (Box 1)
      - C-W, 8 (Box 1)
      - Unidentified, 2 (Box 1)
    - Boardman Trust for Keep & Crane. Resume of M.T.B. Boardman Bio. Sulgrave Red Cross, 1942-57 (Box 1)
    - Breeskin, Adelyn D., 1971-72 (Box 1)
    - Brinn, Lawrence, 1953-74; 2 (Box 1)
    - Burwell, Dr. E. Langdon, 1972-73 (Box 1)
    - Byzantine Evening, 1957 Nov 14 (Box 1)
    - Byzantine Institute Inc., 1956-62 (Box 1)
    - Carracci, Annibale "Apollo and Marsyas", 1941,1945, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Chateau d'Hauterille, undated (Box 1)
    - China Institute, 1929-41; 1980 (Box 1)
    - Chow, Fong, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Christie's, 1978-81; 2 (Box 2)
    - Conde, Carmen, 1974; 1983 (Box 2)
    - Cooke, Dwight: "Africa The Last Continent", 1961 (Box 2)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art. Washington D.C., 1960 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Bruce, 1960-85; 2 (Box 2)
      Includes photographs & articles
    - Crane, Josephine Boardman, 1926-69; 2 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Josephine Boardman, letters from:
      - Beinecke Library, 1973-1976 (Box 2)
        Relates to the Estate and papers of Josephine Boardman Crane (1873-1972).
      - Pybus, Joseph, 8 letters, 1943-45 (Box 2)
      - Quincy, 4 letters, 1909-12 (Box 2)
      - Shiffield, 1889 (Box 2)
      - Ward, undated (Box 2)
    - Crane, Josephine Boardman, estate appraisals, 1973-75 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Louise, letters to Josephine Boardman Crane, 1927-53, undated; 16 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Louise, 1943-93; undated; 3 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Murray, letter from John Woodward, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Stephen, birth certificate, 1978-87 (Box 2)
    - Crane, Winthrop M., Jr., 1954-64; 2 (Box 2)
    - Dalton, Town of [empty], undated (Box 2)
    - Dalton Appraisals, undated (Box 2)
    - Devaud, Berthe, 1937-39; 2 (Box 2)
    - Drewes, William K., "Fine Arts Report" for Josephine Boardman Crane, undated (Box 2)
    - "Driftwood," Woods Hole, Mass., appraisals, 1972 (Box 3)
    - "Driftwood," Woods Hole, Mass., 1947-52 (Box 3)
    - Employees, 1958-68 (Box 3)
    - Engle, Paul, University of Iowa, 1960-64 (Box 3)
    - Family letters, 1958-64 (Box 3)
    - Family letters misc., 1950-86 (Box 3)
    - Fifteenth Street Presbyterian Church, 1960-68 (Box 3)
    - Finley, David E., 1956-61 (Box 3)
    - Foerster, F.W., 1951-55 (Box 3)
    - Forster, Kenneth E., 1960-63 (Box 3)
    - Gibbons, Douglas, Holyday & Ives, Inc., 1965-66 (Box 3)
    - The Hark Company, 1972 (Box 3)
    - The Harpsichord Music Society, 1977-92 (Box 3)
    - Haseltine, Herbert, 1954-55 (Box 3)
    - Hooker, 1944 (Box 3)
    - Henry, William, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Hurt, Jesse, 1961-65 (Box 3)
    - Inventories, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Invitations. Parties, 1955-57 (Box 3)
    - Iranian art and archaeology, 1960 (Box 3)
    - [Irish Literature], 1968-73 (Box 3)
    - Jones, Willie Thomas, 1951-56 (Box 3)
    - Kent, Victoria, incoming, 1976-87; 3 (Box 3)
    - Kent, Victoria, outgoing, 1960-78; 2 (Box 3)
    - Klapthor, Frank E., 1960-73 (Box 3)
    - L & L Foundation, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Lamothe House, 1963-82 (Box 3)
    - Lazare, Christopher, 1981-98 (Box 4)
    - Lindsay, John V., 1964-65 (Box 4)
    - MacIver, Loren, 1968-86; 3 (Box 4)
    - MacIver, Loren, exhibitions, 1960-83 (Box 4)
    - Majewsky, Lawrence, "Istanbul Mosaics-Thursday March 27, 1958" (Box 4)
    - Marlowe, Sylvia, estate appraisals, 1974-82 (Box 4)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1967-80; 2 (Box 4)
    - Michalowski, Roman, 1960-66 (Box 4)
    - Miller, Margaret, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Monday afternoon literary class, 1959-67; 6 (Box 4)
    - Moore, Laurence, 1961-62 (Box 4)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1959-68; 2 (Box 4)
    - National Gallery of Art, Washington, 1955 (Box 4)
    - The National Register and National Historic Landmarks Program, 1977 (Box 4)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1962-87 (Box 4)
    - New England Society for the Preservation of Antiquities, 1970 (Box 4)
    - New York Philharmonic, undated (Box 4)
    - Palmer, Frances E., 1961-67 (Box 4)
    - Parthenon-notes, 1960 Apr 1 (Box 4)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1953-82; 2 (Box 4)
    - Pybus, Joseph, 1933-45; 2 (Box 4)
    - Receipts for art and objects, 1930-98 (Box 4)
    - Receipts for furniture, china, silver, and other objects, 1924-75 (Box 4)
    - Rice, D.S. (archaeologist) (Box 5)
    - Rosenbach Museum (Clive Driver), 1973-74 (Box 5)
    - Russsell, Ellis, 1964-68 (Box 5)
    - Smithsonian Museums, 1970-79 (Box 5)
    - Spark, Victor: art appraisals, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Storrs, Sir Ronald, 1952-54 (Box 5)
    - Szent-Gyorgyi, Dr. Albert, 1968-69 (Box 5)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1977-87 (Box 5)
    - Trinity College, 1955-65 (Box 5)
    - University Microfilms Inc, 1963-75 (Box 5)
    - Washington Cathedral, 1949-58 (Box 5)
    - Wind, Edgar, 1968-76 (Box 5)
    - Woods Hole. Marine Biological Laboratory., 1952-59; 2 (Box 5)
    - Yue, Dr. Shyh-Jong, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Various correspondents, 1938-72; 2 (Box 5)
    - Letters of condolence, 1972; 21 (Box 5)
    - Cards from flower bouquets, undated (Box 5)
  - Personal Papers
    - Yearly planners, 1967-72 (Box 6)
    - Yearly planners, 1973-79 (Box 6)
    - Yearly planners, 1980-86 (Box 6)
    - Diary, 1924 (Box 6)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 6)
    - Various notes, undated (Box 6)
    - Address and telephone books, undated (Box 6)
    - Catalogue of the contents of Louise Crane's library, undated (Box 6)
    - Passports, Louise Crane, 1958-83; 5 (Box 6)
    - Passports, Josephine Boardman Crane, 1934-49; 2 (Box 6)
    - Recipe book, undated (Box 6)
    - Sketch pads, 1968-1975, undated
    - "The Annual Meeting in Lilac Time" by Louise Crane, undated (Box 6)
      Annual meeting of the Advisory Committee of the Fort Hunter Museum
    - Louise Crane medical records from Dr. Anny Baumann, 1950-82 (Box 6)
    - Louise Crane vital records, 1979, undated (Box 6)
    - Leather billfold, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Various invitations, 1986, undated (Box 6)
    - Memorial card for Adolph Berle, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Stationery, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous personal effects, 1963-1982 (Box 6)
    - Various manuscripts, Josephine Boardman Crane and Louise Crane, 1939-42 (Box 6)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane, obituary notices, etc., 1970-74 (Box 6)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane: memorial service, New York, Nov. 1, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane funeral, 1972-73 (Box 6)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane entry in The National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1972-74 (Box 6)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane will, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Clara Loomis Crane last will and testament, undated (Box 6)
    - Check for Miss Malinda Sheffield from James Robb & William Hoge Bank, 1899 (Box 6)
    - "List of Saloon Passengers for R.M.S. 'Servia'", 1888 (Box 6)
    - Resolution by Red Cross regarding Mabel Boardman, 1946 Mar 26
    - Sales contract for property in Vietnam, 1955 (Box 6)
    - All You Want When Traveling in Spain by Charles Hugo, 1932 (Box 6)
    - Colony Club of New York Constitution and By-Laws, list of members, etc., 1980 (Box 6)
    - Postcard collection, undated; 2 (Box 6)
    - Postcard collection, undated; 6 (Box 7)
    - Postcard correspondence, undated; 6 (Box 7)
    - Ruth Stephan poems, undated (Box 7)
    - The Sulgrave Club, anniversary album, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Féeries et Folies program, undated (Box 7)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library pamphlet, 1997-98 (Box 7)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1889; 1908-97; 8 (Box 7)
  - Photographic Materials
    - Slides in "Airequipt Magazine" Boxes
      - Mexico, undated (Box 8)
      - Parad, New Mexico, undated (Box 8)
      - New Mexico, undated; 2 (Box 8)
      - Woods Hole, Massachusetts, Stephen Crane, California, Louise Crane, undated (Box 8)
      - Louise Crane II, undated; 2 (Box 8)
      - Louise Crane III, March 1958; 3 (Box 8)
      - L. FMB [possibly Fort Myers Beach] Witt; Woods Hole, Massachusetts, undated; 4 (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous [possibly Mexico], undated; 2 (Box 8)
      - Painting, undated (Box 8)
      - Blank, undated (Box 8)
    - Loose Slides
      - Woods Hole, Massachusetts, 1965-77; 6 (Box 8)
      - 1968 (Box 8)
      - Artwork, 1969; 2 (Box 8)
      - Home, tombstones, Josephine Boardman Crane, 1973 November (Box 8)
      - 1975 (Box 8)
      - FMB [possibly Fort Myers Beach], undated (Box 8)
    - Photographic Prints and Negatives
      - Louise Crane, 1913-1919; 3 (Box 8)
      - Louise Crane, portrait by David Berns, New York, circa 1930 (Box 8)
      - Louise Crane, portrait from newspaper, [circa 1940] (Box 8)
      - Louise Crane with friends and family, snapshots, 1935-1960s, undated; 3 (Box 8)
      - Louise Crane with friends and family, snapshots, 1970s-1980s, undated; 2 (Box 9)
      - Victoria Kent, Redding, Connecticut, circa 1950s (Box 9)
      - Louise Crane's dog "Roger", undated (Box 9)
      - Josephine Boardman Crane, snapshots, undated; 2 (Box 9)
      - Crane family photograph album, 1960s
      - Josephine Boardman Crane, photograph album, undated (Box 9)
      - Josephine Boardman Crane's 98th birthday, photograph album, undated (Box 9)
      - Stephen Crane, portrait, undated
      - Mabel Boardman, portrait, undated
      - Kaiser Wilhelm, 1895 (Box 9)
      - Unidentified men, portraits, undated (Box 9)
      - School children, undated
      - Photograph album and loose photographs of 820 Fifth Avenue, undated (Box 9)
      - Photographs of untitled paintings, sculpture, undated (Box 9)
      - Photographs of art objects, 1957 (Box 9)
      - Photographs of works not at 820 Fifth Avenue, 1940 (Box 9)
      - Photographs of furniture, 1927 (Box 9)
      - Negatives, 820 Fifth Avenue, dining room salon (Box 9)
      - Negatives and slides, undated (Box 9)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 9)
      - Glass negatives, undated
  - Financial Papers
    - Josephine Boardman Crane Cleveland property, 1931-56 (Box 10)
    - Amendment to trust indenture of June 28, 1928, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1957 (Box 10)
    - The Bank of New York, 1973-86 (Box 10)
    - Statement of Account, estate of Mabel Thorpe Boardman, 1946 (Box 10)
    - First and final account of Josephine Boardman Crane and Bruce Crane, executors of the estate of Florence Sheffield Keep, 1954 (Box 10)
    - First Agricultural Bank Trust division, 1986 (Box 10)
    - American Security and Trust Company, 1948 (Box 10)
    - Bank of New York, 1950 (Box 10)
    - Louise Crane tax deductions 1978, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Healey, John G., undated (Box 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10)
    - Dalton Property-Taxes & Costs, 1957-58 (Box 10)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane Foundation, 1982; 3 (Box 11)
    - Cleveland property, 1974-79 (Box 11)
    - Crane, Bruce, 1979-83 (Box 11)
    - The Bank of New York L. Brinn Trust, 1978-83; 2 (Box 11)
    - Acct. No. 1-312; Indentures, 1956-1978 (Box 11)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane Foundations-incorporations, by-laws, tax returns, 1973-74 (Box 11)
    - Estate - Josephine Boardman Crane, 1972-76 (Box 11)
    - Louise Crane Foundation Bank of New York, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Louise Crane Foundation: gifts, 1970-82 (Box 11)
    - Foundations: Louise Crane, 1979-84 (Box 11)
    - Louise Crane Foundation, 1962-81 (Box 11)
    - Income tax returns, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Louise Crane Foundations, account info., 1983 (Box 11)
    - Taxes: Louise Crane, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Tax Deductions: Louise Crane, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Tax Deductions: Louise Crane, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Taxes: Louise Crane, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Tax Deductions: Louise Crane, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Taxes: Louise Crane, 1976-81; 5 (Box 11)
    - Taxes, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Taxes, 1982-83 (Box 11)
    - By-Laws of Josephine B. Crane Foundation, undated (Box 11)
    - Bank of New York Trust #1, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Bank of New York LCF, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Brinn-custodian accounts, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane foundation statements, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Taxes: Louise Crane, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Sugar Hill Trust, undated (Box 12)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane statements, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Josephine Boardman Crane Trust 1 1221 Agricultural National Bank, 1977-81 (Box 12)
    - Trusts # 1222 & 1223, 1978-79 (Box 12)
    - A.G. National Bank #1-1222, 1980-81 (Box 12)
    - A.G. National Bank: #1223, 1977-81 (Box 12)
    - A.G. National Bank Statements, 1982-83 (Box 12)
    - American Security Bank, N.A. statement, 1983 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank, 1977 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank-Trust 1225, 1975-79 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank Trust 1-516; income, 1973-81 (Box 12)
    - The Bank of New York statements, 1975-80 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank, 1983 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank Trust 1-516: principle, 1971-80 (Box 12)
    - Agricultural Bank: # 125, income, 1976-81 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank: Trust 1-516: indenture, undated (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank Trust 125: principle, 1972-80 (Box 12)
    - Great grandchildren trusts, 1979-81 (Box 12)
    - Crane, Bruce, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Amendment to Trust Indenture of June 28, 1928, 1978 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank: 1225 (S. Crane), 1980-81 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank statements, 1974-80 (Box 12)
    - A.G. Bank: trust 125: indenture, 1944-83 (Box 12)
    - American Security & Trust Co. Washington, D.C., 1970-82 (Box 12)
    - Agricultural Bank - Trust 312 Income, 1974 (Box 12)
    - A.G. National Bank, 1972-73 (Box 12)
    - A.G. National Bank, 1965-71 (Box 12)
    - Trust I-312 income, 1976-81 (Box 12)
    - Bank of New York, 1978-79 (Box 12)
    - Lawrence E. Brinn, 1982-83 (Box 12)
    - First Agricultural Bank: Walter Wheat, 1979-83; 2 (Box 12)
    - First Agricultural Bank #1-25, 1981 (Box 12)
    - First Agricultural Bank #1-516, 1980-81 (Box 12)
    - First Agricultural Bank #1-1221, 1980-81 (Box 12)